

Vijay Rajan Machingauth

Engineering Manager Technical

338 W Rincon Ave, Campbell, California, US, CA 95008

(408)-797-4215

vijay.rajan@gmail.com

English, Tamil, Malayalam, Hindi





BACKGROUND



Building & leading high-velocity teams focused on delivering complex products, experience managing cross-geo teams, server SoC power management, firmware validation, arch/micro arch debug in pre/post-si env, ARM and X86 architectures, CAD tools development for microprocessors/graphics, C, C++, python, perl & ruby, emulation bring up/debug/collateral development

WORK EXPERIENCE

 Senior Engineering Manager Technical, IPG, Intel Corporation, Intel Corporation Nov. 2015 - Present

Lead the server power management firmware validation and the Intel server manageability IP development teams - reponsible for delivery of zero-defect power management FW for all Intel server products & Intel server manageability IP. Also lead the power-management IP emulation strategy

Senior Chief Engineer, Validation Architect, Samsung India Software Operations, Bangalore Jul, 2014 - Sep, 2015 ① 1 year 2 months

Senior Chief Engineer and Validation Architect responsible for validation strategy for Exynos mobile SoCs. simulation, emulation, multi-IP validation & multi-processor validation strategies

Technical Lead, Post-Silicon Validation, Intel Technology India Pvt Ltd

May, 2012 - Jun, 2014 **③** 2 years 1 month

Lead a team focused on Xeon power management post-silicon validation. Driving test content development, execution and debug. Responsibilities include content and execution planning, failure debug for internal and externally reported issues.

o Lead power management post-si validation of Jaketown, Ivytown and Broadwell Server

Technical Lead, Post-Silicon Debug and Debug tools, Intel Technology India Pvt Ltd Jul, 2010 - Jun, 2014 ③ 3 years 11 months

Lead a team developing post-silicon debug tools. These tools are used for the post-si system debug of Intel multi-core Xeon Microprocessors. validation of power management features and manual debug of failures.

Technical Lead, SV tools, Intel Technology India Pvt Ltd

